goape.co.uk 2019-10-29

# Privacy Policy | Go Ape | GoApe

Your privacy is important to us. We take great care with how we collect, store and use your personal information.

### 1.1 Who Are We?

We are Adventure Forest Ltd trading as Go Ape. Our head office address is Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK. You should address any enquiries about our use of your personal data to our Data Protection Officer (DPO) by post, by email at [**data.privacy@goape.co.u**](mailto:data.privacy@goape.co.uk)k or by telephone on ** _+44 (0)1284 771048_**.

### 1.2 HOW TO USE THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it sets out how Go Ape collects and uses personal information about you, according to the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) and is regularly reviewed. This privacy notice was last updated on 18 May 2018. Please check these pages from time to time to ensure you are aware of any updates that we may make, and that will take effect as soon as they are made.  

### 1.3 What this notice covers

This policy covers the personal information we may hold about you, however we obtain it. We collect information at different points during our relationship with you. For example, when you browse our website, sign up to receive marketing, make a booking for one of our activities or sign a disclaimer at the site where you participate in any activity. This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site to other websites and we encourage you to read the privacy statements on other websites you visit.   

### 1.4 what is meant by 'personal data'?

Personal data means any information relating to an individual which can identify them, directly or indirectly. It includes a wide range of identifying information such as name, email address, postal address, mobile number, location and genetic data, social identity, IP address and so on.  

This privacy notice tells you what to expect when Go Ape collects your personal information. We will tell you what information we collect, why we use it, how long we will keep it and who we share it with. The notice applies to information we collect about you when you engage with us, including in any of the following ways:

 **When you use our online channels**

  * Browse our website
  * Engage with our social media channels
  * Participate in our Live Webchat service
  * Request a quote
  * Buy a gift voucher

 **When you respond to or ask for marketing**

  * Enter one of our competitions
  * Sign up to receive direct marketing
  * Sign up to receive partner marketing
  * Respond to a market research survey

 **When you visit a Go Ape site**

  * Make a booking
  * Agree to having your photo used
  * Sign a disclaimer or warranty
  * Are involved in an incident
  * Receive medical attention
  * Give an online review

 **When you contact Go Ape for other reasons**

  * Apply for a job
  * Contact our call centre
  * Apply for charity gift vouchers

### 2.1 WHEN YOU USE OUR ONLINE CHANNELS

Go Ape has a website and several social media channels that you can visit and engage with, including Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube and Google. Through our website you can find out about all the different Go Ape adventures, sites and facilities. The scenarios below explain how we collect and use your data when you use our online channels in these ways.

 **BROWSE OUR WEBSITE**

 **What information do we collect?**

We collect information about your computer such as browser, network location, type of connection and device, IP address. This is done using cookies – see our Cookie Policy for more information.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

The type of information gathered is to determine how the website is working and enable us to improve its information and functionality to continuously improve the user experience to our website users. We sometimes use the information to display a Go Ape advert to you whilst you are visiting other websites that offer this service. We also analyse the data collected in an anonymised way; looking at the overall usage and trends through reporting and analysis.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep the information on servers operated by our hosting provider, and also with our analytics provider which is based in the US but compliant with Europe’s data protection legislation under the Privacy Shield programme.

 **Who do we share it with?**

This data is for our own use and we do not share it further.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Most of the data is collected as part of our analytics service and we have agreed with our provider to keep the data on an ongoing basis. In addition, each cookie type retains information for a different length of time. See our Cookie Policy for more information.

 **ENGAGE WITH OUR SOCIAL MEDIA CHANNELS**

 **What information do we collect?**

We collect information about your engagement with Go Ape on our social media sites, such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Trustpilot, YouTube and Google.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

When you respond to one of our adverts or posts by clicking a link that takes you to our website, we track that activity from a special cookie or tag that the social media platform uses and reports to our analytics tool. We collect this information to help us understand the success of our advertising, the type of content and information you like, and other social activity, which helps us plan future campaigns and communications of interest to our target customers.

We analyse the data collected in an anonymised way; looking at the overall usage and trends that the collective data provides through reporting and analysis.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep the information on servers operated by our hosting provider, and with our analytics provider which is based in the US but compliant with Europe’s data protection legislation under the Privacy Shield programme.

 **Who do we share it with?**

The analytics data is for our own use and we do not share it further.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Most of the data is collected as part of our analytics service and we have agreed with our provider to keep the data on an ongoing basis. In addition, each cookie type retains information for a different length of time. See our Cookie Policy for more information.

 **PARTICIPATING IN OUR LIVE WEB CHAT SERVICE**

We offer an online service so that you can communicate directly and quickly with a member of our call centre through the website. The conversation ‘transcripts’ stay for 30 days in our webchat partner’s server and are kept for issue resolution and training purposes.

 **REQUEST A QUOTE**

 **What information do we collect?**

When you request a quote from us using a web form, or by phone, you give us your name, email and phone number as part of your enquiry.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We will use this information, combined with the other information you gave us (company, activity and site of interest) to put together an adventure that we think will suit your needs and to provide you with the quote for this.

 **Where do we look after it?**

Your information will be stored in our bookings system and customer database, operated by our hosting our providers.

 **Who do we share it with?**

The analytics data is for our own use and we do not share it further.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We will keep your data for five years following our last communication with you, after which your details will be deleted from our systems.

 **BUY A GIFT VOUCHER**

When you buy a gift voucher, you will follow the same online purchase process as in the ‘Make a Booking’ section below.

### 2.2 when you visit a go ape adventure site

You can make a booking for any of our Go Ape adventures on our website, by contacting our call centre, or when you arrive at a Go Ape site. Before you can take part in your Go Ape adventure, you will need to sign a disclaimer, possibly more than one if you have additional support needs. Sometimes we may ask your permission to take photos and video footage of you experiencing your Go Ape adventure for use in our marketing. If you are involved in an accident or incident we have a process that we need you to follow, which will include the potential collection of additional information.

 **MAKE A BOOKING**

 **What information do we collect?**

When you make a booking with us, whether online, by phone, with our call centre or on site, we require certain personal information to deal with your booking. The following is generally required as minimum: name, email address, phone number, postal address, and payment card details or information relating to your company for group bookings. If you have any additional needs, you may need to provide more information.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

The information we request from you is required to finalise your booking including taking your payment, and to ensure we can provide your activity. If you require additional physical assistance to access and enjoy the activities we offer, the extra information you give to us will help. It also helps us to comply under equality legislation.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep your information in our booking system and customer databases, operated by our hosting providers.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We will also share certain details with other companies that we work with under contract to process your payment and fulfil your booking, such as with our payment partner.

After your Go Ape adventure, we share your email address with our customer experience partner, Trust Pilot, which invites you to review and post your experience with us on their platform.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We keep your details for a minimum of five years after your Go Ape adventure.

 **AGREE TO HAVE YOUR PHOTO TAKEN AND USED**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you give your consent to having photos or video taken we will ask for the following information: name, email address, mobile number, signature and whether you are under 16 or not. For children under 16, we will collect these details for the parent/guardian of each child, plus the name of the child(ren).

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We may use these images across our full range of marketing and media channels and applications which promote and publicise Go Ape. This may include digital and print content and materials such as our website, blog, social media, posters, advertisements, email content, leaflets and other publicity materials.

Footage will not be used in conjunction with any other information that could identify you, unless we have gained your express permission beforehand. Such instances could include for a press article which may name you, or as a competition winner on a social media channel.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep all footage that we are actively using on servers operated by our hosting provider. Once we stop using the photos and video, we will destroy most of it but will keep selected footage that we used as a historical archive on the same servers.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We will not sell the images but may share them with third parties, as may be needed in the production and dissemination of our marketing materials, such as designers, printers, advertisers, journalists, third party re-sellers. We may also share them with other companies and organisations with whom we engage in joint promotional activities, such as suppliers of other leisure services or products. Images used on our social media channels may also be shared by our active followers. Although we have clear terms of use of materials set out in our Website Terms of Use Policy it is possible that other third parties will take and use images on our website or other digital channels without our permission – that’s just the nature of the web.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Go Ape has a policy to actively use images for up to 10 years. Again, due to the nature of the web, some images may remain ‘out there’ for longer. We may also keep images that have been used in marketing activity in our archive library as a historic record of our brand and promotional development and these may remain indefinitely. 

**RISK ACKNOWLEDGEMENT DISCLAIMERS**

 **What information do we collect?**

When you book a Go Ape adventure with us, you will be asked to read and sign a Risk Acknowledgement and Disclaimer for each activity, providing your name, age and signature. A parent, guardian or carer must sign for each child under 16 years of age that they are supervising.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We ask for this information to ensure you have read and understood the risks of taking part in the activity, as they can all be dangerous if instructions and safety measures are not followed. The forms are used in the event of any claim and helps improve safety standards by tracking any accidents, should they occur.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We save the information on the paper form you signed and keep it in the booking office onsite for three months after your visit. The forms are then moved to our central storage facility.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We do not share this information unless you have an accident whist at a Go Ape site or other issue that needs to be investigated in which case we may need to share the form with, for example, parents of a child you were supervising, our solicitors or insurers, or other agencies as may be required by law – see ‘Sharing due to legal requirements’ section below.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Forms will be kept for a period sufficient to cover Limitation Act claims. Consequently, most forms will be kept for four years. Those relating to individuals under the age of 18 may be kept until they are 21 years of age.

 **MEDICAL AND RELIGIOUS DISCLAIMERS**

 **What information do we collect?**

When you book a Go Ape adventure with us, if you have any pre-existing medical conditions or needs, cultural or religious traditions that impact your ability to safely take part in the activity, you will be asked to read and sign an additional disclaimer. In each instance we will collect your name and signature, but some forms require additional information. Each child under 18 years of age must be signed for by either a parent, guardian or carer, dependent on the disclaimer.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We issue disclaimers for the following:

Religious headwear - If you are unable or unwilling to wear the protective helmets for our Forest Segway experience, due to a cultural or religious tradition of wearing a headscarf or turban, we will ask you to sign a form declaring this.

Pregnancy - If you are pregnant but still wish to take part in an activity we will ask you to sign a form declaring this.

Existing physical injury or condition - If you have a pre-existing injury or condition but still wish to take part in an activity we will ask you to sign a form declaring this including providing details of the injury or condition. 

Hearing impaired - If you have hearing difficulties we will agree with you any additional adjustments to the safety brief to assure your safety and will ask you to sign a form agreeing to follow these rules.

Additional needs - If you have a medical or physical disability we will ask you to declare the needs which are to be accommodated. We may agree to provide you with additional assistance or increased supervision and will ask you to sign a form agreeing to this.

We ask for this information to ensure you have read and understood the additional risks of taking part in the activity. This is a legal requirement to ensure:

  * we have brought the risks to your attention;
  * where appropriate we have devised additional support in accordance with your specific conditions;
  * you have understood and accepted any additional risks and agree to any additional rules and support.

The forms are used in the event of any claim and to help improve safety standards by tracking any accidents, should they occur.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We save the information on the paper form you signed and keep it in the booking office onsite for three months after your visit. The forms are then moved to our central storage facility.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We do not share this information unless you have an accident whist at a Go Ape site or other issue that needs to be investigated, in which case we may need to share the form with, for example, medical personnel if you need medical attention, our solicitors or other agencies as may be required by law – see ‘Sharing due to legal requirements’ section below.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Forms will be kept for a period sufficient to cover Limitation Act claims. Consequently, most forms will be kept for four years. Those relating to individuals under the age of 18 may be kept until they are 21 years of age.

 **ACCIDENTS AND INCIDENTS**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you have an accident whether causing injury or not, we will collect details on a form about the event including at minimum your name, age, gender, address, phone number and the same for the adult who was supervising you and any other customers involved but not injured.

Similarly, if you are involved in an incident we will collect your name, age, gender, address, phone number.

It may also be necessary to take injury details, witness statements and photographs to document what happened.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We will collect this information so that we can comply with our policies and any legal requirements to investigate what happened, ensure our first-aider and any other medical professionals tending to you can provide you with the appropriate care, and take any other administrative actions required. It is required by law to keep a record of accidents and treatment, and to register attendance by a medical professional. The forms are also used in the event of any claim and to help improve safety standards by tracking any accidents, should they occur.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We transfer the information on the paper form to an online database operated by our hosting partners as soon as possible and destroy the paper copies. On occasion, some paper copies are moved to our central storage facility, together with any disclaimers you would have signed. 

**Who do we share it with?**

We do not share this information unless with, for example, medical personnel if you need medical attention; our solicitors or other agencies as may be required by law – see ‘Sharing due to legal requirements’ section below. 

**How long do we keep it for?**

We keep the information in case there is a claim about the cause of the accident and/or the treatments received. information will be kept for a period sufficient to cover Limitation Act claims. Consequently, most forms will be kept for four years. Those relating to individuals under the age of 18 may be kept until they are 21 years of age.

### 2.3 MARKETING ACTivITIES

Go Ape offers a range of competitions, promotions, surveys and news to its customers and prospective customers, which you are welcome to sign up to, or participate in. This may include you signing up to marketing with one of our competition partners or, indeed, signing up to receive Go Ape marketing through one of our partners’ competitions or promotions.

 **SIGN UP TO GO APE DIRECT MARKETING**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you sign up to receive our marketing emails we will as a minimum collect your name and email address. If you also consent for other forms of direct marketing such as SMS or post, we will also ask for your mobile number or postal address.

If you have signed up to receive marketing alongside another action such as when you made a booking or requested a quote, we will not request any additional information.

 **Why and how do we use it?**

We will use this information to send you marketing from time to time, which includes updates on Go Ape activities, discounts, competitions and other news we feel may be of interest to you.

The marketing emails you receive may contain tracking cookies within the email, used to record activity by recipients such as opening, forwarding or clicking links. This is tracked and stored in a database for analysis and evaluation, used to refine future email campaigns and supply you with more relevant content. For further information please refer to our Cookie Policy.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep your information in our bookings system and customer databases operated by our hosting partners, including those based in the US but who are compliant with EEA a data protection legislation under the Privacy Shield programme.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We will also share your data with other partners we work with under contract in the fulfilment and administration of our marketing, including our email host provider or mailing house. Aside from such instances we will not share your information with others unless we have your permission to do so.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

Go Ape has a policy to only keep an individual’s data on the marketing list for up to two years since their last visit to Go Ape or engagement with the marketing content that we sent to you. That way we know only to keep in touch if you are still interested in our news, or can take you off our list so that you don’t get emails you’re no longer interested in.

 **ENTER A COMPETITION OR PRIZE DRAW**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you entered a competition or prize draw through our website or at a Go Ape location, we will collect your name and email address as a minimum, to accompany your entry, whether a prize draw or a skill-based competition.

 **Why do we collect and use it?**

We need this so that we can administer the competition or prize draw and contact the winner(s) to arrange their prize.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep your information in customer databases operated by our hosting partners, including those based in the US but compliant with EEA a data protection legislation under the Privacy Shield programme.

 **Who do we share it with?**

Our call centre partner, Open Contact, will be given the winners’ information to arrange delivery of the prize(s). Often our competitions are run jointly with other organisations offering leisure or related services or products. If the partner is also offering a prize we will share the winner’s details with the partner, so they can arrange its delivery.

If you opted-in to receive marketing from the competition partners, then we will share your data with them also.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We will keep details of those who entered a competition for a month after the winner has been successfully selected and contacted to arrange delivery of the prize(s), after which the entries will be destroyed.

 **SIGN UP TO RECEIVE DIRECT MARKETING FROM A GO APE PARTNER**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you enter one of our competitions, you may also be asked if you would like to opt-in to receive direct marketing from the competition partners. If you agree, we will collect at minimum your name and email address.

 **Why do we collect and use it?**

We will use this information to pass over to our partner(s) as you will have given your consent to receive direct marketing from the partner who will use it to send you email newsletters, postal or other types of direct mail, according to the consent you gave.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep your information in customer databases operated by our hosting partners.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We will share this information with the partners you gave consent for.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We will keep it for two years after you signed up for the marketing.

Note that our third-party partners will have their own policies for how long they will retain your information, so you should look at the privacy policies on their websites.

 **SIGN UP TO A COMPETITION OR GO APE DIRECT MARKETING THROUGH A PARTNER**

Go Ape will sometimes enter joint promotional activity with commercial partners, typically other organisations offering products or services in the leisure or related industry. In many cases Go Ape will host and administer the competitions, but sometimes our partners will, and in such cases, they will collect data on our behalf.

If you were the winner of a competition one of our partners hosted and administered, our partner will send us your information, so we can arrange your prize. See ‘Enter a competition or prize draw’ above.

If you opted-in to receive direct marketing from Go Ape, our partner will send us your details. See ‘Sign up to Go Ape direct marketing’ above.

### 2.4 OTHER REASONS YOU MAY SHARE PERSONAL DETAILS WITH GO APE

 **APPLY FOR A JOB**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you apply for a job with Go Ape, you will complete an online application form, giving us at minimum your name and email address along with your CV including previous job titles and places of employment.

 **Why do we collect and use it?**

We need this information so that we can assess your suitability for the role you apply for and so that we can invite you for interview if your application is successful.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep your information in our servers operated by our hosting partners.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We do not share your information further.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We will keep your details for 12 months from the date of application. If you are successful and come to work with Go Ape, you will be advised of how your personal data will be used and stored during the offer process.

 **CONTACT OUR CALL CENTRE**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you telephone our call centre, your name and phone number are taken as minimum.

 **Why do we collect and use it?**

We need this information so that staff can use your name in the conversation, phone you back if the line was disconnected in error or use it in case of any litigation or query resolution. Depending on the nature of your enquiry e.g. to make a booking or request a quote, the relevant process and data collection will be followed – see the other reasons for processing in this Privacy Notice.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We record all telephone calls made to our call centre, for issue resolution and training purposes. Our call centre is run by our partner, Open Contact, which looks after the recordings and any other data taken on its servers in the EEA.

 **Who do we share it with?**

We do not share your information further unless there is a claim or other issues requiring it to be shared with external agencies, for example, our solicitors.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We will keep the recordings for two years from the date of your call.

 **APPLY FOR CHARITY GIFT VOUCHERS**

 **What information do we collect?**

If you apply for some vouchers to use as a raffle or other prize at a community or charity fund-raising event, you will give us your name email address and phone number, along with details about the charity you are supporting.

 **Why do we collect and use it?**

We will use this information to contact you if your application is successful and to arrange your vouchers and any leaflets you require to be sent to you.

 **Where do we look after it?**

We keep this information in our customer database operated by our hosting partner.

 **Who do we share it with?**

This information is for our own use and we do not share it further.

 **How long do we keep it for?**

We keep the information until we have confirmation that you have received the vouchers and leaflets, and the delete it from our system.

**DIRECT MARKETING**

If you have given us your consent to receive marketing communications from us by email, we will send you emails from time to time about our news, offers, competitions and activities. If you signed up to receive our email school newsletters or email corporate newsletters, then you will receive these more frequently. Occasionally we may also send communications by post or text if you have agreed to this.

 **TARGETED MARKETING**

We use segmenting techniques to ensure that the communications and offers we send you are personalised, timely and relevant based on your activity and interaction with us to date. We may consider such factors as the type of Go Ape adventure you went on, your postcode or preferred site, and if you have previously entered competitions with us. We do this to try to improve your Go Ape opportunities and experience and to help ensure that you only receive communications and offers that are likely to be of interest to you.

We do not provide your personal information to external organisations for their own marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

 **SOCIAL MEDIA TAREGTED MARKETING**

We will use your personal data to participate in certain targeted advertising services offered by some social media channels, such as Facebook’s Custom Audience and Google’s Customer Match, so that you can receive targeted ads from us when you use the social media sites. We may use encrypted versions of your email address or phone number for this purpose.

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services. See our Cookies Policy and audit for more details of the types of cookies we use and how you block them if you wish.  

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you will always be stored on our secure servers or those of our service providers. Unless otherwise stated in the individual scenarios in Section 3 above, it will be stored within the EEA*.

However, some of our providers are based in the US or other countries outside of the EEA which may have lower standards of protection for personal data than Europe enjoys. So, if your information does go outside of Europe we will transfer and store it with partners that are either signed up to the Privacy Shield (US companies) or have agreed to contractual terms that we set – in all cases they will be compliant with European data protection legislation.

* EEA is the European Economic Area which includes EU, EFTA (European Free Trade Association = Iceland, Norway, Switzerland, Liechtenstein).

If you want to know more about how we keep your data secure when it is transferred internationally, please contact us using

 **SHARING DUE TO LEGAL REQUIREMENTS**

In some circumstances, we may have to disclose your personal information by law, because a court or the police or other law enforcement agency has requested it using the appropriate channels. This includes but is not limited to enforcement authorities for the Reporting of Injuries, Diseases and Dangerous Occurrence Regulations, the Health and Safety at Work Act 1974, and any other necessary regulations as part of an enforcement visit or investigation.

 **HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?**

We only hold your personal information for as long as is necessary for the reason you provided it to us, as per the processing scenarios described in the sections above. In some cases, there are statutory obligations or industry best practise reasons that dictate the length of time for which we will hold your information. For example, if you make a complaint or feel you may have a legal claim against us, then we will hold your information for the duration of any statutory limitation period associated with such incidents.

We are committed to ensuring that your information is safe and secure whilst under our control to protect against loss, unauthorised disclosure or access. We have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers or those of our service providers and any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.  

 **REPORTING A SECURITY INCIDENT**

If at any point you suspect or become aware of a security incident (for example you receive suspicious communication from someone purporting to be a Go Ape employee or affiliate), please forward the communication to us or report it by email to **[data.privacy@goape.co.uk](mailto:data.privacy@goape.co.uk) **or in writing to Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK.

If you have been the victim of a fraudulent transaction, please always contact the police and/or your bank in the first instance to ensure your own finances are secure.

**ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION**

Go Ape tries to be as open as it can be in terms of giving people access to their personal information. Individuals can find out if we hold any personal information by making a ‘subject access request’ under the GDPR. If we do hold information about you, we will:

  * give you a description of it;
  * tell you why we are holding it;
  * tell you who it could be disclosed to; and
  * let you have a copy of the information in an intelligible form.

To make a request to us for any personal information we may hold you need to put the request in writing addressing it to our DPO or writing to the email or postal addresses provided below.

We will try to deal with your request informally in the first instance, for example by providing you with the specific information you need over the telephone.

 **CHANGES TO YOUR INFORMATION**

If your details change, or if you think that any of the information that we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us with any changes you would like made at the contact details below

Similarly, if you would like to object to any ways in which your data is being processed including removing your consent for marketing, contact our DPO at the details below.

 **REMOVING YOUR CONSENT FOR DIRECT MARKETING**

If you have given us your consent to receive marketing messages from us, you can change your mind and remove your consent (opt-out) at any time. Here are the ways you can contact Go Ape to do this: click the ‘unsubscribe’ option at the end of a marketing email; email us at **[data.privacy@goape.co.uk](mailto:data.privacy'goape.co.uk)** ; or write to us at Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK. It may take up to two weeks for your details to be removed from our marketing list.

Please note that if you have a forthcoming Go Ape adventure booking we will send you service-related emails, even if you have unsubscribed from marketing communications as this is important information you will require for your activity.

 **REMOVING YORU CONSENT FOR USE OF YORU IMAGES**

You can withdraw the consent you gave for us using your image at any time. For children whose parents/legal guardian gave permission on their behalf, when they turn 16, they have legal rights over this data and will have the right to revoke the consent themselves. To withdraw your consent email [**data.privacy@goape.co.uk**](mailto:data.privacy@goape.co.uk); or write to us at Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK.

We will stop using your images as soon as reasonably possible but note that images used for web-based promotions may remain indefinitely.

 **QUERIES AND COMPLAINTS**

Go Ape tries to meet the highest standards when collecting and using personal information. For this reason, we take any complaints we receive about this very seriously. We encourage people to bring it to our attention if they think that our collection or use of information is unfair, misleading or inappropriate, or if you do not think that we have processed your data in accordance with this notice. We would also welcome any suggestions for improving our procedures.

Although it may seem lengthy, this privacy notice was drafted with brevity and clarity in mind. It does not provide exhaustive detail of all aspects of Go Ape’s collection and use of personal information. However, we are happy to provide any additional information or explanation needed. Any requests for this should be sent for the attention of our DPO at the address below.

If you want to make a complaint about the way we have processed your personal information, you can contact us, again through our DPO:

  * By telephone on **+44 (0)1284 771048**
  * By email at [**data.privacy@goape.co.uk**](mailto:data.privacy@goape.co.uk)
  * By post Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK.

We will respond to your enquiry within five working days but may take 30 days to investigate and resolve your concern. If your query will take longer than this to investigate and resolve, we will let you know how long it will take.

If you are not satisfied with our response, you can refer the matter to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). Information about how to do this is on the ICO website at [**www.ico.org.uk**](https://ico.org.uk/)

 **HOW TO CONTACT US**

If you need to contact us in relation to data protection including exercising your rights regarding your personal information including any of the reasons above, you can contact our DPO:

  * By telephone on _**+44 (0)1284 771048**_
  * By email at **_[data.privacy@goape.co.uk](mailto:data.privacy@goape.co.uk)_**
  * By post Go Ape, Banana HQ, The Drift, Fornham St Martin, Suffolk IP31 1SL, UK.
